New England Medical Center Records MS099
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
New England Medical Center Records
1920 -- 1990
1880 -- 2009
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Boston Floating Hospital
Tufts Medical Center
Boston Dispensary
Pratt Clinic/New England Center Hospital
School of Medicine
Tufts-New England Medical Center
MS099
391.6 Linear Feet
2 Volumes
2 Artifact(s)
161 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 19 series: Photographs and audiovisual materials; Reference material; Administration records; Departments; Personnel records; Finance records; Development office records; Legal counsel records; Corporate Public Affairs office records; Planning office records; Architectural/Engineering Services records; Frances Stern Nutrition Center records; Rehabilitation Center records; Ladies Committee records series; NEMC International; Publications; Oversized material and artifacts; Archives of the New England Medical Center Hospitals records; and Legacy collection documentation.
Custodial History
This collection was originally part of the archives of the New England Medical Center (NEMC), which closed in 1990. The collection was processed under the leadership of Dave Nathan, archivist at the NEMC archives. from 1985 - 1990, and had the following NEMC acquisition numbers: 83-14, 87-1, 83-3, 84-2, 84-14, 84-30, 84-22, 84-32, 84-39, 85-15, 85-8, 85-11, 85-20, 85-36, 85-12, 85-19, 86-9, 86-14, 86-17, 88-1, 89-10, 89-20, 83-13, 84-36, 84-40, 85-4, 85-7, 85-9, 87-9, 84-9, 84-28, 85-12, 86-39, 86-40, 86-41, 87-26, 88-15, 87-30, 89-5, 89-12, 84-18, 88-1, 84-33, 85-18, 85-47, 85-16, 86-59, 86-60, 86-61, 86-62, 86-56, 84-6, 84-7, 84-30, 84-35, 85-37, 86-4, 85-17, 85-37, 86-64, 86-28, 86-55, 87-36, 88-3, 88-12, 84-41, 86-63, 86-66, 87-8, 83-4, 86-18, 86-32, 86-50, 85-1, 86-24, 84-34, 86-52, 85-34, 86-12, 86-53, 86-33, 87-32, 83-1, 84-9, 84-18, 84-24, 84-32, 84-39, 84-42, 86-23, 86-28, 86-39, 86-40, 86-41, 86-42, 86-55, 86-57, 87-7, 87-11, 87-26, 87-31, 87-36, 89-11.
In spring 2013, NEMC material was transferred from NEMC to a restoration company for conservation treatment, and was then transferred to off-site storage in custody of Digital Collections and Archives (DCA). In December 2014 and January 2015, the material was transferred to DCA for processing. Some material originally in the NEMC archives was not transferred to DCA, due to either poor condition or loss.
Scope and Contents
The records of the New England Medical Center (NEMC) contain the administrative, financial, legal, publicity, and departmental records of the institution. The collection also contains extensive audiovisual material; timelines and reference files relating to NEMC's history; publications by and for NEMC; planning files for the expansion of NEMC; and the records of affiliated organizations, such as the Frances Stern Nutrition Center and the Ladies Committee. Of particular interest are the Photographs and audiovisual material series (MS099.001), which contains hundreds of photographs depicting physicians, staff, patients, procedures, and NEMC buildings, dating back to the 1890s, and the Reference material series (MS099.002) which contains historical reference information, including a timeline of events from 1665 to 1992.
As there was a periodic shifting of departments to and from NEMC/T-NEMC and their constituent institutions, any comprehensive search of a particular topic over time must involve also consulting the other NEMC archives collections at DCA. Contact DCA for information about associated material of this collection.
This collection suffered extensive water damage due to a flood before it was in the custody of DCA. It underwent conservation efforts before processing, but several materials, particularly folders, scrapbooks, and bound volumes, are still warped or retain a musty odor. In addition, many items are fragile, and must be handled carefully.
DCA will forward to Tufts Medical Center all requests for permission to reproduce archival materials not in the public domain.
Related Materials
MS214, Boston Dispensary records, DCA
MS213, Boston Floating Hospital records, DCA
MS220, Ralph Deterling papers, DCA
MS221, Samual Proger papers, DCA
MS222, Pratt Clinic/New England Center Hospital records, DCA
MS224, Tufts-New England Medical Center records, DCA
MS228, Bingham Associates Fund records, DCA
Biographical / Historical
The New England Medical Center (NEMC) is the principal teaching hospital for the Tufts School of Medicine and School of Dental Medicine. The Medical Center's chiefs of service are joint appointees with the medical school and most serve as chairs of their respective departments at the medical school. Students take 25% of their required third year clerkships and 50% of their fourth year electives at NEMC.
Recognizing that education and research are essential components to good medical care, the New England Medical Center was established in 1930 through the alliance of the Boston Dispensary, the Boston Floating Hospital for Infants and Children, and the Trustees of Tufts College. The NEMC was established as a non-profit corporation to coordinate the administrative activities of its constituent organizations. In 1946 the Joseph H. Pratt Diagnostic Hospital, an extension of the Boston Dispensary established in 1938, joined NEMC. In 1950, when the Medical School and Dental School relocated to Harrison Avenue, the NEMC became known as the New England Medical Center Hospital.
The entity was renamed Tufts-New England Medical Center in 1968, and in 1970 the NEMC board met at the Coonamessett Inn in Falmouth, Massachusetts to outline ways the NEMC and Tufts could further coordinate operations. The resulting directives, known as the Coonamessett Statement, indicated that support services and other business functions should be made the responsibility of T-NEMC in each case where it made sense to do so. That same year Tufts President Hallowell and NEMC President Quarles signed an affiliation agreement that codified the T-NEMC as an alliance through which its constituent units would move toward a completely integrated operation. By 1976, T-NEMC controlled health care studies, medical engineering, community health and ambulatory care, employee-student health services, lab animal medicine, some research, off-site medical services, a common utility supply center, architectural services, communications, educational media, parking facilities, property ownership, and public relations. However, by the late 1970s both institutions had experienced a change in leadership, resulting in a change of priorities for each. Interest in integration waned and the cooperation forged in the early 1970s was dismantled.
After a period of tension and competition in the 1980s, Tufts and NEMC drafted a new affiliation agreement in 1991, which remains in effect as of 1999. In 2000, the center was once again named Tufts-New England Medical Center, or T-NEMC.
New England Medical Center; Tufts-New England Medical Center; Tufts Medical Center; Grossman, Jerome; Vigeurs, Richard; Field, Hermann H.; Stern, Frances; Dunks, Abby; Katz, Geneva; Boston Floating Hospital for Infants and Children; Boston Dispensary; Pratt Diagnostic Hospital; New England Center Hospital; South End Diet Kitchen; Frances Stern Nutrition Center; Tufts College. Medical School; Tufts University. School of Medicine; Hospitals; Medical care; Free medical care; Bingham Associates Fund; Physicians; Nurses; Patient care; Health care; University history; Medical history; Medicine -- History
- Photographs and audiovisual material, 1880 -- 2009; MS099.001; 86.8 Linear Feet; 1 Artifact(s); 159 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains images, films, and audio recordings in various formats. Images in the collection depict individuals, buildings, activities, and subjects belonging to, or affiliated with, NEMC and its predecessor organizations. Several images are duplicates and can be found in a variety of formats throughout the series.
  All print images are in black and white. Print image folders are titled with a subject heading identifying what is depicted in the photograph, as well as the photograph's institutional affiliation (Boston Floating Hospital, BFH; Boston Dispensary, BD; Pratt Clinic-New England Medical Center, PC/NECH; New England Medical Center, NEMC; Tufts-New England Medical Center, T-NEMC).
  Transparencies, slides, audio, and video were created by the Educational Media Center. Transparencies and slides are often duplicates of the print images. Slides and audiovisual material include presentations and marketing material for NEMC and its staff.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged into seven groups: Photographs, subjects and buildings; Photographs, individuals affiliated with NEMC; Transparencies; Educational Media Center; Glass slides; Audiotapes; and Videotapes.
  Conditions Governing Access
  75 years from the date of creation. Open for research.
  - Photographs, subjects and buildings, 1880 -- 1990; MS099.001.001
    Open for research.
    - Admitting Department - Boston Dispensary, 1914 -- 1916; MS099.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
      - Adult patients in the waiting room, 1914; MS099.001.001.00001.00001 (Box 1)
        Adult patients in Boston Dispensary's waiting room.
        Boston (Mass.); Medical care; Patients (LCSH); Waiting rooms; photographic print; Boston Dispensary
      - Boston Dispensary's clinic waiting room, 1916; MS099.001.001.00001.00002; Hine, Lewis W. (Box 1)
      - Seeing the doctor gives them an appetite, 1914; MS099.001.001.00001.00003 (Box 1)
        Mothers with infants awaiting doctor at Boston Dispensary clinic.
    - Admitting Department - Boston Floating Hospital, 1894 -- 1927; MS099.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
    - Admitting Department - Boston Floating Hospital, 1927 -- 1965; MS099.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
    - Aerial Photographs, 1950 -- 1969; MS099.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
    - Aerial Photographs, 1970; MS099.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
    - Allergy and Immunology - Boston Dispensary, MS099.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
    - Anesthesia - PC/NECH, MS099.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
    - Anniversaries and Special Events, 1957 -- 1964; MS099.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
    - Anniversaries and Special Events, 1965; MS099.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
    - Anniversaries and Special Events - Boston Dispensary, MS099.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
    - Anniversaries and Special Events - Boston Floating Hospital, 1931 -- 1934; MS099.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
      - Center Building cornerstone laying, 1931-01-26; MS099.001.001.00011.00001 (Box 1)
        Boston (Mass.); Buildings; photographic print; Boston Dispensary
      - Girl with life preserver, 1934; MS099.001.001.00011.00002 (Box 1)
        BFH: heroine of BFH publicity movie "A Floating Hospital on Dry Land"
        photographic print
    - Anniversaries and Special Events - Lowell Lecture Series, 1968; MS099.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
    - Art, 1920 -- 1930; MS099.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
      - Wood carving of the Good Samaritan and a nurse, 1920 -- 1930; MS099.001.001.00013.00001; Rittase, William (Box 1)
        Boston (Mass.); Nurses; Art; photographic print; Boston Dispensary
    - Awards and Prizes, MS099.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
    - Awards and Prizes - Volunteers, MS099.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
    - Awards and Prizes - Personnel, 1953 -- 1969; MS099.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
    - Awards and Prizes - Personnel, 1970; MS099.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
    - Balconies - BFH, 1927 -- 1965; MS099.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
    - Biomedical Engineering, 1960 -- 1980; MS099.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
      - Biomedical engineering, 1960 -- 1980; MS099.001.001.00019.00001 (Box 1)
        Boston (Mass.); Biomedical engineering; photographic print
    - Blood Bank, MS099.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
    - Blood Banks - PC/NECH, MS099.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
    - Blood Transfusion - Boston Floating Hospital, 1927 -- 1965; MS099.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
    - Blood Transfusion - PC/NECH, MS099.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
    - Boston Dispensary, 1910; MS099.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
      - Social worker at the Boston Dispensary interviewing mother and children, 1910; MS099.001.001.00024.00001 (Box 1)
        Boston (Mass.); Patients (LCSH); Social workers; photographic print; Boston Dispensary
    - Boston Dispensary Records - NECH Ground Breaking Ceremonies, MS099.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
    - Boston Floating Hospital, 1906 -- 1920; MS099.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
      - A young girl is being treated for whooping cough, using x-rays, at the Onshore Department of the Boston Floating Hospital, 1920; MS099.001.001.00026.00001; T.E. Marr and Son (Box 1)
        Boston Harbor (Mass.); photographic print; Boston Floating Hospital for Infants and Children
      - Toddlers on the Boston Floating Hospital ship's sundeck, 1920; MS099.001.001.00026.00002 (Box 1)
      - BFH Ship: Bottling of Mother's Milk, 1906; MS099.001.001.00026.00003; T.E. Marr and Son (Box 1)
      - BFH Ship: Shoeshine boy on deck, 1906; MS099.001.001.00026.00004 (Box 1)
    - Buildings (37 Bennet Street), MS099.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
    - Buildings - Biewend (260 Tremont Street), 1975; MS099.001.001.00028 (Box 1)
      - Biewend building exterior, 1975; MS099.001.001.00028.00001; Bernstein, Daniel (Box 1)
        Boston (Mass.); Buildings; photographic print; Biewend
    - Buildings - Center (Nassau Street) - Anniversaries and Special Events, MS099.001.001.00029 (Box 1)
    - Buildings - Farnsworth (171 Harrison Avenue) - Exteriors, 1940 -- 1965; MS099.001.001.00030 (Box 1)
      - Farnsworth building exterior, 1950 -- 1965; MS099.001.001.00030.00001 (Box 1)
      - Farnsworth building plaque, 1949; MS099.001.001.00030.00002 (Box 1)
        Boston (Mass.); photographic print; New England Medical Center
      - Farnsworth building architectural rendering, 1940 -- 1950; MS099.001.001.00030.00003 (Box 1)
    - Buildings - Farnsworth (171 Harrison Avenue) - Interiors, 1949; MS099.001.001.00031 (Box 1)
      - Farnsworth Surgical building clinic lounge, 1949-05-23; MS099.001.001.00031.00001 (Box 1)
        Inez Gordon, R.N., checks appointments while patients wait their turn.
        Boston (Mass.); Hospitals; photographic print; Gordon, Inez; New England Medical Center
    - Buildings - Floating Hospital - Anniversaries and Special Events, 1982; MS099.001.001.00032 (Box 1)
    - Buildings - Floating Hospital - Anniversaries and Special Events, 1982; MS099.001.001.00033 (Box 1)
      - Ted Kennedy and Mondale, 1982-10; MS099.001.001.00033.00001; Sherman, Stephen (Box 1)
        Boston (Mass.); photographic print; Kennedy, Edward Moore, 1961-; Boston Floating Hospital for Infants and Children
    - Buildings - Floating Hospital - Dedication - Donors Luncheon - Wong Center, 1983; MS099.001.001.00034 (Box 1)
    - Buildings - Floating Hospital (796 Washington Street) - Anniversaries and Special Events, MS099.001.001.00035 (Box 1)
    - Buildings - Floating Hospital (796 Washington Street) - Construction, MS099.001.001.00036 (Box 1)
    - Buildings - Floating Hosptial (796 Washington Street) - Exteriors, MS099.001.001.00037 (Box 1)
    - Buildings - Floating Hospital (796 Washington Street) - Models, MS099.001.001.00038 (Box 1)
    - Buildings - Garage (Tremont Street), MS099.001.001.00039 (Box 1)
    - Buildings - Hemenway (11 Nassau Street), 1927 -- 1965; MS099.001.001.00040 (Box 1)
    - Buildings - Holmes (49 Bennet Street), 1960 -- 1970; MS099.001.001.00041 (Box 1)
      - Holmes building, 1964-04; MS099.001.001.00041.00001 (Box 1)
        The Holmes building, located at 177 Harrison Avenue, before renovation into a coffee shop.
      - Holmes building, 1960 -- 1970; MS099.001.001.00041.00002; Lenscraft Photos, INC. (Box 1)
        Boston (Mass.); Buildings; photographic print; New England Medical Center
    - Buildings - Jackson (20 Ash Street) - Anniversaries and Special Events, MS099.001.001.00042 (Box 1)
    - Buildings - Jackson (20 Ash Street) - Exteriors, 1931; MS099.001.001.00043 (Box 1)
      - Jackson Memorial building plaque, 1931; MS099.001.001.00043.00001; Maskell, Harry (Box 1)
        Plaque formerly in Jackson Memorial building, Ash street and Nassau street, commemorating the bequest from the estate of Henry Clay Jackson and Paul Wilde Jackson which enabled the Boston Floating Hospital to build this, its first land-based building.
        Boston (Mass.); Signage; photographic print; Boston Floating Hospital for Children
    - Buildings - Jackson (20 Ash Street) - Interiors, MS099.001.001.00044 (Box 1)
    - Buildings - Pratt (30 Bennet Street) - Anniversaries and Special Events, MS099.001.001.00045 (Box 1)
    - Buildings - Pratt (30 Bennet Street) - Exteriors, 1930 -- 1940; MS099.001.001.00046 (Box 1)
      - Pratt building entrance, 1930 -- 1940; MS099.001.001.00046.00001; Paul J. Weber Architectural Photography (Box 1)
        Boston (Mass.); Hospitals; photographic print; Pratt Clinic/New England Center Hospital
    - Buildings - Pratt (30 Bennet Street) - Interiors, 1930 -- 1950; MS099.001.001.00047 (Box 1)
      - William Bingham dedication plaque, 1930 -- 1950; MS099.001.001.00047.00001; Paul J. Weber Architectural Photography (Box 1)
        Boston (Mass.); photographic print; Bingham, William II (1879-1955); New England Medical Center
      - Pratt Diagnostic Hospital entrance, 1935 -- 1945; MS099.001.001.00047.00002 (Box 1)
    - Buildings - Proger (750 Washington Street) - Construction, 1970; MS099.001.001.00048 (Box 1)
      - Building the Orange Line, 1970; MS099.001.001.00048.00001; Bernstein, Daniel (Box 1)
        At construction - Dental tower construction with Orange Line tunnel exposed.
        Boston (Mass.); Construction; photographic print; Tufts University School of Dental Medicine; New England Medical Center
    - Buildings - Proger (750 Washington Street) - Drawings, MS099.001.001.00049 (Box 1)
    - Buildings - Proger (750 Washington Street) - Exteriors, MS099.001.001.00050 (Box 1)
    - Buildings - Proger (750 Washington Street) - Interiors, MS099.001.001.00051 (Box 1)
    - Buildings - Rehabilitation Institute (185 Harrison Avenue) - Exteriors, MS099.001.001.00052 (Box 1)
    - Buildings - Seybolt Plaza (Washington Street), MS099.001.001.00053 (Box 1)
    - Buildings - Ziskind (Harvard Street) - Anniversaries and Speical Events, 1940 -- 1980; MS099.001.001.00054 (Box 1)
      - Man in front of test tubes, 1940 -- 1960; MS099.001.001.00054.00001 (Box 1)
        Boston (Mass.); Laboratories; Research; photographic print; Tufts University. School of Medicine
      - Two women in laboratory, 1950 -- 1980; MS099.001.001.00054.00002 (Box 1)
      - Ziskind building directory, 1959; MS099.001.001.00054.00003; Magna Film Productions, Inc.; Public Relations Department Tufts-New England Medical Center (Box 1)
        Boston (Mass.); Buildings; photographic print; Pratt Clinic/New England Center Hospital; New England Medical Center
    - Cancer Institute (Fishman, W.), 1894 -- 1927; MS099.001.001.00055 (Box 1)
    - Cardiology, MS099.001.001.00056 (Box 1)
    - Cardiology - Child. BFH, 1927 -- 1965; MS099.001.001.00057 (Box 1)
    - Cardiology - Division, 1927 -- 1965; MS099.001.001.00058 (Box 1)
    - Central Supply, MS099.001.001.00059 (Box 1)
    - Central Supply - PC/NECH, MS099.001.001.00060 (Box 1)
    - City and Town Life - Chinatown, MS099.001.001.00061 (Box 1)
    - Clinical Research Centers, MS099.001.001.00062 (Box 1)
    - Communicable Diseases, MS099.001.001.00063 (Box 1)
    - Community Health Services, MS099.001.001.00064 (Box 1)
    - Community - Institutional Relations, 1894 -- 1927; MS099.001.001.00065 (Box 1)
    - Community Mental Health Services - Facilities, MS099.001.001.00066 (Box 1)
    - Community mental Health Services - Patient Care, MS099.001.001.00067 (Box 1)
    - Community Mental Health Services - Personnel, MS099.001.001.00068 (Box 1)
    - Dental Service, MS099.001.001.00069 (Box 1)
    - Dermatology, MS099.001.001.00070 (Box 1)
    - Daithermy - BD, MS099.001.001.00071 (Box 1)
    - Diathermy - BFH, 1894 -- 1927; MS099.001.001.00072 (Box 1)
    - Dictating Machines, MS099.001.001.00073 (Box 1)
    - Dietary Services - Infant - BFH, 1894 -- 1927; MS099.001.001.00074 (Box 1)
    - Dietary Services - Infant - BFH, 1927 -- 1965; MS099.001.001.00075 (Box 1)
    - Drawings - BD, MS099.001.001.00076 (Box 1)
    - Emblems and Insignia, MS099.001.001.00077 (Box 1)
    - Emergency Medical Services, MS099.001.001.00078 (Box 1)
    - Endocronology, 1938 -- 1945; MS099.001.001.00079 (Box 1)
      - Geiger counter in Endocrinology lab, 1938 -- 1945; MS099.001.001.00079.00001 (Box 1)
        PC/NECH: Lab technician using Geiger counter in Endocrinology laboratory on a white rat in research on Endocrinology.
        Boston (Mass.); Laboratory technicians; Geiger counters; photographic print; Joseph H. Pratt Diagnostic Hospital; New England Center Hospital
    - Financial Management, MS099.001.001.00080 (Box 1)
    - Food Service, MS099.001.001.00081 (Box 1)
    - Food Service - BFH, 1894 -- 1927; MS099.001.001.00082 (Box 1)
      - BFH ship: lunch served to children at other end of open-air deck, 1920; MS099.001.001.00082.00001; T.E. Marr & Son (Box 1)
        Boston Harbor (Mass.); Medical care; Food service; photographic print; Boston Floating Hospital for Infants and Children
    - Food Service - PC/NECH, MS099.001.001.00083 (Box 1)
    - Fundraising, MS099.001.001.00084 (Box 1)
    - Governing Board - PC/NECH, MS099.001.001.00085 (Box 1)
    - Governing Board - T-NEMC, Inc, MS099.001.001.00086 (Box 1)
    - Hematology, MS099.001.001.00087 (Box 1)
    - Hematology - PC/NECH, MS099.001.001.00088 (Box 1)
    - Hemodialysis Units, 1960 -- 1980; MS099.001.001.00089 (Box 1)
      - Renal dialysis, 1973-05-25; MS099.001.001.00089.00001; Bernstein, Daniel (Box 1)
        Boston (Mass.); Hemodialysis; photographic print; New England Medical Center
      - Renal dialysis, 1973-05-25; MS099.001.001.00089.00002; Bernstein, Daniel (Box 1)
    - Home Care Services - BD, 1911; MS099.001.001.00090 (Box 1)
      - District physician on his rounds, 1911; MS099.001.001.00090.00001 (Box 1)
        Boston Dispensary district physician on rounds with visiting nurse and neighborhood children.
        Boston (Mass.); Medical care; Physicians; photographic print; Boston Dispensary
    - Hospital Design and Construction - Anniversaries and Special Events - Master Plans, 1961 -- 1973; MS099.001.001.00091 (Box 1)
    - Hospital Design and Construction - Maps - Master Plans, 1955 -- 1973; MS099.001.001.00092 (Box 1)
    - Hospital Design and Construction - Personnel - T-NEMC Planning Office, MS099.001.001.00093 (Box 1)
    - Hospital Design and Constuction - Models - Master Plans, 1961 -- 1973; MS099.001.001.00094 (Box 1)
    - Hospital Design and Construction - Dfrawings - PC/NECH, MS099.001.001.00095 (Box 1)
    - Hospital Design and Construction - Drawings - Master Plans, 1970; MS099.001.001.00096 (Box 1)
      - Tufts Dental Health Sciences building, 1970-12-30; MS099.001.001.00096.00001 (Box 1)
        Architectural drawing of Tufts Dental Health Sciences building, Phase I on Kneeland street.
        Boston (Mass.); Architectural drawings; photographic print; Tufts-New England Medical Center; New England Medical Center Hospital
    - Hospital Ships - Exterior at Sea. BFH, 1906; MS099.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
      - Boston Floating Hospital ship, 1906; MS099.001.002.00001.00001; T.E. Marr and Son (Box 2)
        Side view of the second Boston Floating Hospital ship at sea.
        Boston Harbor (Mass.); Ships; photographic print; Boston Floating Hospital for Infants and Children
      - Drawing of BFH ship, 1906; MS099.001.002.00001.00002 (Box 2)
        Boston Floating Hospital's second ship under construction, from a painting by Thomas R. Neil.